Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Ranch House Records, 1921, 1945-1960s, 1975-1976, 1980s, 1999-2007, and undated IA20021
Institutional Records and Archives
- Architectural drawings, 1921; 1945-1951,; 1975-1976,; undated; Series III.; 15 Linear Feet (15 flat files)
  - Art gallery renovation:
    - "Mr. Paul Getty, 2nd Floor Room, Jensen, Inc.,", April 25, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Mr. J. Paul Getty, 1st floor Room. Jensen Inc.,", April 25, 1951 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-6)
    - "Art Gallery Mr. Paul Getty. Los Angeles, Calif. Room. Louis XVI. 2nd Floor,", 1951; [Dated in pencil.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-9)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: Ground Floor Plan,", March 5, 1975; [9 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-10)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: Second Floor Plan,", March 5, 1975; [11 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-10)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: Ground Floor Plan,", June 25, 1975; [4 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-10)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: Second Floor Plan,", June 25, 1975; [4 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-10)
  - "Floor Plan of Guest House,", April 25, 1975; [2 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - "Floor Plans of Employees' Cottages,", April 25, 1975; [3 copies.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - "Suggested additions for servants' quarters – ground floor plan,", August 15, 1975 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - "Suggested additions for servants' quarters – second floor plan,", August 15, 1975 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: First Floor Plan." March 5, 1975, revised, January 22, 1976 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence, Malibu California: Second Floor Plan." March 5, 1975, revised, January 22, 1976 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - [Column design, cross sections], undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-12)
    ["34" on verso.]
  - [Column design, cross sections], undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-12)
  - "Paul Getty Ranch, Santa Monica,", undated; [Pencil Drawing, with chalk.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-12)
  - [Sketch for wall design], undated; ["47" on verso. In pencil.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-12)
  - [Annotated 1st floor plan], undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
  - [Annotated second floor plan], undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
  - "J. Paul Getty Residence Ground floor plan,", March 5, 1975; [Photocopy.] (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
  - [Rear (?) elevation], undated; [2 copies.] (Flatfile 2004.IA.13-2)
- Photographs and miscellaneous file, circa 1950s-1960s; 1980s,; 1999-2007,; undated; Series IV.; 1 Linear Feet (3 boxes and 1 binder)
  These records are arranged by accession.
  Records consist of 6 black and white photographs and 45 color photographs, mid-1980s and undated, of the J. Paul Getty Ranch House. The photographs depict the house before, during, and after the renovations of gallery space to office, and conservation and laboratory space; these renovations were carried out after the opening of the Villa rendered the gallery spaces unnecessary.
  - [6 black and white photographs of the Ranch House before renovation], undated (Box 1986.IA.27-1)
    [The photographs depict Ranch House interiors, primarily office spaces.]
  - [10 5" x 8" inch photographs of the Ranch House during renovation, taken by Mitchell Hearns Bishop], circa 1980s (Box 1986.IA.39-1, Folder 1)
  - [35 8" x 10" inch photographs of the Ranch House during renovation, taken by Mitchell Hearns Bishop], circa 1980s; [1 of 2] (Box 1986.IA.39-1, Folder 2)
  - [35 8" x 10" inch photographs of the Ranch House during renovation, taken by Mitchell Hearns Bishop], circa 1980s; [2 of 2] (Box 1986.IA.39-1, Folder 3)
  - Fredericksen: "Original Ranch House, Grounds, and Museum,", circa 1960s; 0.2 Linear Feet (1 binder) (Box 2010.IA.04-01)
    Scope and Contents
    These photographs have been attributed to Burton Fredricksen. Contains 116 color prints and 2 black-and-white prints of the original Ranch House, galleries, grounds, and animals as well as corresponding photographic slides. Prints are approximately 5 x 7 inches each.
  - Photos of Ranch house maintained by Villa librarian, circa 1950s; (1 folder) (Box 2010.IA.04-02)
    Contains photographs of the Ranch House, grounds, and galleries maintained by Villa librarian Barbara Furbush. Contains 14 black-and-white prints, 3 color prints (approximately 8 x 10 each) and 1 hand-tinted print. Also contains a partial inventory of the photographs, an email related to the photographs, and 4 photographic negatives.
  - Ranch House subject file maintained by Villa librarian, 1960s-2007; (1 folder) (Box 2010.IA.04-02)
    File contains photocopies of various sources of information on Mr. Getty and the Ranch House such as newspaper clippings, photographs, publications, and lists of archival resources found at non-Getty repositories. This material was collected and maintained by Barbara Furbush, Villa librarian.